- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[light music]
[轻音乐]
*
[bubbles popping]
[气泡破裂]
- News flash!
A severe rip current
- 新闻快讯！
严重的离岸电流
may soon touch down
in Bikini Bottom.
可能很快就会着陆
在比基尼底部。
Residents are warned
to bar all windows
居民被警告
禁止所有窗口
and stay indoors.
并留在室内。
[hammering]
[锤击]
[cow moos]
[牛哞哞]
Save yourselves!
救救你们自己吧！
- Ahh, rip current,
schmip current.
- 啊，离岸流，
施米普电流。
'Tain't nothing.
“没什么。”
- Gee, Mr. Krabs,
do you think the rip current
- 哎呀，蟹老板先生，
你认为离岸流
will hit the Krusty Krab?
会击中蟹堡王吗？
Ahh!
[imitates explosion, splashing]
啊！
【模拟爆炸、飞溅】
[screaming,
explosion noises]
[尖叫，
爆炸声]
- Uh, shouldn't we
clear the docks?
- 呃，我们不应该吗
清理码头？
Or batten down the patches?
还是把补丁打平？
Or whatever people say?
还是人家说啥就啥？
- Calm your waters!
- 平静你的水域！
Me sailor's knee
says we're not in danger, see?
我水手的膝盖
说我们没有危险，明白吗？
[whistling, ticking]
[口哨声，滴答声]
Now, get back to work!
现在，回去工作吧！
- Excuse me, are we in
any kind of peril?
- 打扰一下，我们在吗？
有什么危险吗？
- I think we should
all go home.
- 我认为我们应该
都回家吧。
- As soon as you buy some
Patties to go, you can go.
- 一旦你买了一些
肉饼要走了，你可以走了。
- I'll have three
Krabby Patties.
- 我要三个
蟹肉饼。
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
On second thought,
cancel that order!
再一想，
取消该订单！
- No takey-backsees!
Three Krabby Patties.
- 没有收回！
三个蟹肉饼。
[buzzing]
[gasps]
[嗡嗡声]
[喘气]
Me money detector!
Where do you think you're going?
我的金钱探测器！
你认为你要去哪里？
Get back in there
and spend the rest
回到那里
并度过剩下的时间
of your money!
- But I needed it for rent.
你的钱！
- 但我需要它来出租。
- Listen up, everybody!
New store policy:
- 大家听着！
新店政策：
all money
brought into this store
所有的钱
带进这家店
must be spent here.
一定要在这里度过。
- Tyrant!
- 暴君！
- Oh! Tyrant am I?
- 哦！我是暴君吗？
All right,
I'm a tyrant!
好吧，
我是暴君！
The worst in all
the seven seas.
最糟糕的
七大洋。
What of it?
[growls]
那又怎样呢？
[咆哮]
- Hey, why's Mr. Krabs
so crabby today?
- 嘿，为什么是蟹老板
今天这么暴躁吗？
- Probably because
it's payday.
- 可能是因为
今天是发薪日。
- Payday's been canceled!
[feedback squeals]
- 发薪日已取消！
[反馈尖叫声]
Now hear this!
I'm the captain of this ship!
现在听听这个！
我是这艘船的船长！
Captain Krabs!
蟹老板！
And I say no rip current
我说没有离岸电流
will ever harm
the Krusty Krab!
永远会伤害
蟹堡王！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[crashing]
[chains rattle]
[崩溃]
[链条嘎嘎作响]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[all screaming]
[crashing]
[所有人尖叫]
[崩溃]
[yelling]
[大喊]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[wood creaks]
[木头吱吱作响]
[thud]
[砰]
[crashing]
[崩溃]
[pained groan]
[痛苦的呻吟]
[duck quacks]
[鸭子嘎嘎叫]
- Darn arthritis.
- 该死的关节炎。
[creaking]
[吱吱作响]
[chains rattle]
[链条嘎嘎作响]
[yelling]
[grunting]
[大喊]
[咕噜声]
[all screaming,
whimpering]
[大家尖叫，
呜咽]
- [growls]
Hm.
- [咆哮]
嗯。
[thrilling music]
[key jangles]
[惊心动魄的音乐]
[关键铃声]
Yah.
嗯。
*
Yah!
Wah!
啊！
哇！
*
[straining effort]
[用力]
[popping]
- Ah!
[爆裂声]
- 啊！
- Squidward,
while I steer,
- 章鱼哥，
当我驾驶时，
you tell everyone
we're safe.
你告诉大家
我们很安全。
- It's all right now,
everybody.
- 现在没事了
大家。
- Everything's under control
now and whatever.
- 一切尽在掌握
现在以及无论如何。
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
- Three cheers
for Squidward!
- 三声欢呼
为了章鱼哥！
- The guy who saved
our lives.
- 拯救的人
我们的生活。
- Let's make him
our new captain.
- 让我们让他
我们的新队长。
- Hip, hip--
- 臀部，臀部--
all: Hooray for
Captain Squidward!
全部： 万岁
章鱼哥船长！
- Congratulations,
Squidward.
- 恭喜，
章鱼哥。
Oh, I mean
Captain Squidward.
哦，我是说
章鱼哥船长。
- What's the meaning
of this?
- 是什么意思
这个？
- What should we do with this
tyrant, Captain Squidward?
- 我们应该用这个做什么
暴君，章鱼哥船长？
- Captain Squidward?
- 章鱼哥队长？
- Let's flog him!
- 我们来鞭打他吧！
all: Yeah!
全体：是啊！
- Let's tie him
to the mast!
- 我们把他绑起来
到桅杆！
all: Yeah!
全体：是啊！
- Let's put
the past behind us
- 让我们把
过去在我们身后
and start all over!
一切从头开始！
all: No!
全体：不！
- This is mutiny!
Listen here, Squidward.
- 这是叛变！
听着，章鱼哥。
Fun is fun,
but get me out of here!
好玩就是好玩，
但带我离开这里！
- Sorry, I don't think
that's a captain's job.
- 抱歉，我不认为
这是队长的工作。
You're on your own.
- Hey, everybody,
你只能靠你自己了。
- 嘿，大家，
can we take a time out?
我们可以抽出时间吗？
This is Mr. Krabs
we're talking about.
这是蟹老板
我们正在谈论。
The worst tyrant
in the seven seas.
最坏的暴君
在七大洋中。
- You're not helping, boy.
- 你没有帮忙，孩子。
- You remember Mr. Krabs.
- 你还记得蟹老板。
He's the man
who brought you
他就是那个男人
谁带你来的
the Krabby Patty!
[bell dings]
蟹肉饼！
[铃声]
[all agreeing]
[全部同意]
And he's the man who brought you
the double Krabby Patty.
他就是那个把你带来的人
双克拉比帕蒂。
And the Krabby Patty
with Cheese.
还有蟹黄饼
与奶酪。
- [yells]
- And the Bratty Patty
- [大喊]
- 还有顽皮的帕蒂
for kids.
- Um, little help here.
对于孩子们。
- 嗯，没什么帮助。
- He also created
the Chatty Patty for teens.
- 他还创造了
适合青少年的闲聊帕蒂。
And who can forget
the Hatty Patty,
谁能忘记
哈蒂·帕蒂，
the patty you wear
as a hat?
你穿的小馅饼
作为帽子？
- I wear it
because I'm bald.
- 我穿它
因为我是秃头。
- Well, I guess any man
who invented
- 嗯，我想任何人
谁发明的
the Hatty Patty
can't be all bad.
哈蒂·帕蒂
不可能都是坏事。
Okay, let's get him out.
好吧，我们把他弄出去吧。
- Whoa!
- 哇！
Man overboard!
男人落水了！
[yells]
[喊叫]
- No!
- 不！
Mr. Krabs!
蟹老板！
- Well, I guess that solves
that problem.
- 嗯，我想这可以解决
那个问题。
["Taps" playing]
[“点击”播放]
[bites, chews,
swallows]
[咬、咀嚼、
燕子]
- I know you'll come back
to us, Mr. Krabs!
- 我知道你会回来的
给我们，蟹老板！
Until then--
[slurps]
到那时——
[啜饮]
I'll leave a dollar
in the window for you.
我会留下一美元
在窗口为你。
- Hey! It's Captain Squidward's
fault that we lost the man
- 嘿！这是章鱼哥船长的
错的是我们失去了那个人
who invented
the Hatty Patty.
谁发明的
哈蒂·帕蒂。
- Yeah, we're fickle
and we say
- 是的，我们善变
我们说
you're the tyrant now!
all: Yeah!
你现在就是暴君了！
全体：是啊！
Uhh, don't be hasty.
呃，别着急。
Remember, I'm--
I'm still the captain.
请记住，我是——
我还是队长。
The Hatty Patty
was my idea!
哈蒂·帕蒂
是我的主意！
- But we're still stuck
in this rip current!
- 但我们仍然陷入困境
在这撕裂的电流中！
- We'll never get out!
- 我们永远出不去！
- Oh--
[stammers]
- 哦--
[结巴]
Ooh!
[flapping sound, struggles]
哦！
[拍打声，挣扎]
Oh, barnacles!
It--ow--oh, oh!
哦，藤壶！
它——噢——噢，噢！
[metal clanging]
[金属叮当作响]
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
[grunting, crashing]
[咕噜声，崩溃]
[straining]
[紧张]
[screams]
[popping]
[尖叫声]
[爆裂声]
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
[crashing]
[崩溃]
- Uh, We're alive!
- 呃，我们还活着！
Captain Squidward
steered us
章鱼哥船长
引导我们
out of the rip current!
脱离离岸流！
- How 'bout a cheer
for Captain Squidward?
- 欢呼一下怎么样
章鱼哥队长？
[all cheer]
[大家欢呼]
Thank you, thank you.
Just doing my job as captain,
谢谢，谢谢。
只是尽我队长的职责
protecting my crew.
保护我的船员。
- Whoa, where are we?
[all exclaim]
- 哇，我们在哪里？
[所有人惊呼]
- Oh, look at that.
That's amazing.
- 哦，看看那个。
太棒了。
- This neighborhood's crazy.
- 这个街区太疯狂了。
I wonder if there are
any good places to eat.
不知有没有
有什么好吃的地方。
- You think
maybe they've got
- 你认为
也许他们有
a Krusty Krab
around here?
蟹堡王
这附近？
- Hey, good idea.
I could go
- 嘿，好主意。
我可以去
for a Krabby Patty.
- I'm calling
蟹肉饼。
- 我打电话来
the local Krusty Krab
right now.
当地的蟹堡王
现在。
[dial tone, dialing]
[拨号音、拨号]
[phone rings]
- Hello, Krusty Krab.
[电话铃声]
- 你好，蟹堡王。
- Yes, I'd like to
place an order.
- 是的，我愿意
下订单。
- Oh!
[slamming]
- 哦！
[砰]
[phone rings]
[电话铃声]
[roaring, crashing]
[all scream]
[咆哮、撞击]
[所有人尖叫]
- Monster! Monster!
- 怪物！怪物！
[roars]
[怒吼]
- Captain!
- You gotta save us.
- 队长！
- 你得救我们。
[squishing]
[groans]
[压扁]
[呻吟]
Ahh!
Captain Squidward!
啊！
章鱼哥船长！
Um, I know where he is.
嗯，我知道他在哪里。
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[straining]
Ooh!
[紧张]
哦！
[thud, grunts]
- Uh, Captain,
[重击声，咕噜声]
- 呃，队长，
sorry to interrupt,
but the crew needs you
抱歉打扰，
但船员需要你
to protect them.
- Are you crazy?
保护他们。
- 你疯了？
I can't fight a monster!
我无法与怪物战斗！
- Oh, I'm afraid
the crew insists, sir.
- 哦，我害怕
船员们坚持要求，长官。
[all growling]
[全都咆哮]
[gulps]
[吞咽]
- I don't wanna
be captain!
- 我不想
当队长！
I don't wanna be captain!
我不想当队长！
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
all: [straining effort]
Yah!
全部：[用力]
啊！
- [screams]
- [munches]
- [尖叫]
- [咀嚼]
- Well, that was
anticlimactic.
- 嗯，那是
虎头蛇尾。
- Maybe he'll make
the monster sick.
- 也许他会做
怪物生病了。
- Okay, who had their money on
Captain Squidward?
- 好吧，谁有钱
章鱼哥队长？
Pay up.
付钱吧。
- Well, somebody has to
step up, fight that monster,
- 好吧，总得有人这么做
站起来，对抗那个怪物，
and become captain.
并成为队长。
And that somebody is me!
那个人就是我！
[straining]
[紧张]
[popping]
[breathing heavily]
[爆裂声]
[呼吸粗重]
[breathes, sniffs]
[呼吸，嗅]
[gags]
[笑点]
[gulps, gargles]
[吞咽，漱口]
[swallows, coughs]
[吞咽，咳嗽]
Hi-ya!
嗨呀！
Huh.
呵呵。
Hi.
你好。
Huh?
Boink.
啊？
操。
Oh, what was I doing now?
哦，我现在在做什么？
[screaming]
[gasping]
[尖叫]
[喘气]
[crashing, grunting]
[崩溃，咕噜声]
- Hm.
- Mr. Krabs!
- 嗯。
- 蟹老板！
You're alive!
你还活着！
Oh, welcome back, Captain!
哦，欢迎回来，船长！
- Haven't you
forgotten something?
- 你没有吗
忘记了什么？
I am not captain anymore.
我不再是队长了。
Squidward is.
章鱼哥是。
- Uh-uh.
The monster ate him.
- 呃呃。
怪物吃了他。
We need a captain,
and that's you!
我们需要一位队长，
那就是你！
Isn't that right?
是不是这样？
[all agreeing]
[全部同意]
- Why would I want
to be captain
- 为什么我想要
当队长
to such a sorry bunch
of lubbers?
致这群令人遗憾的人
笨蛋？
I'm through.
[roaring, glass shatters]
我已经结束了
[咆哮，玻璃碎裂]
- And that's coming out
of your pay!
- 那就要出来了
你的工资！
- Mr. Krabs,
this job calls for
- 蟹老板先生，
这项工作需要
a dictator like you!
像你这样的独裁者！
- Hm.
[roaring, glass shatters]
- 嗯。
[咆哮，玻璃碎裂]
- Do something,
Mr. Krabs!
- 做点什么，
蟹老板！
- Beg me.
[all begging]
- 求我吧。
[大家都在乞讨]
- We're begging.
Please!
- 我们在乞求。
请！
[growling, slurping]
[咆哮，吸食]
- Not buying it.
[all begging]
- 不买。
[大家都在乞讨]
[shimmering tone]
[闪烁的音调]
- Got it!
- 知道了！
Do you know
what this is, Mr. Krabs?
你知道吗
蟹老板，这是什么？
- I don't care.
- It's the first dime
- 我不在乎。
- 这是第一毛钱
you ever earned,
and I'm going to tear it up
你曾经赚到的，
我要把它撕碎
if you don't go back
to being
如果你不回去
存在
the meanie we need.
我们需要的吝啬鬼。
- I said I don't care.
- 我说我不在乎。
- Okay, here goes.
- 好的，开始了。
[straining effort]
[用力]
Ah.
Ahh, wah!
啊。
啊，哇！
[metal clangs, shatters]
[金属叮当作响，破碎]
Ah.
啊。
[saw buzzes]
[看到嗡嗡声]
- My leg!
- 我的腿！
- Ha, you lose.
- 哈，你输了。
- Hm.
Oh!
- 嗯。
哦！
Well then, I'm gonna do
the worst thing
那么，我要做
最糟糕的事情
I can do
to your old dime.
我可以做
到你的旧一角钱。
- Oh, yeah?
What's that?
- 哦，是吗？
那是什么？
- Spend it.
- 花掉它。
[metal clangs]
- Huh?
[金属叮当声]
- 啊？
Hmm.
唔。
Oh, no you don't!
Come here!
哦，不，你不！
过来！
Gah!
[thud]
嘎！
[砰]
All right, everybody!
What am I?
好吧，大家！
我是什么？
all: Um--
[glass shatters]
全体：嗯——
[玻璃碎裂]
- Come on.
It starts with a T.
- 快点。
它以 T 开头。
- A tree?
- 一棵树？
- A teddy bear?
- 泰迪熊？
- A tuba?
- 大号？
- You're a tyrant?
- 你是暴君？
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all: A tyrant!
[cheering]
全体：暴君！
[欢呼]
- Correct!
All right, I'll save ya.
- 正确的！
好吧，我来救你。
But you've got to promise
to spend most of your--
但你必须保证
花费你的大部分时间——
all of your money right
here, got it?
你所有的钱都对
在这里，明白了吗？
[all agreeing]
[全部同意]
[roars]
[screaming]
[怒吼]
[尖叫]
- Hold onto me dime,
boy-o.
- 抓住我一毛钱，
男孩-o。
[growls]
[咆哮]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[growls]
[咆哮]
[screaming stops]
[尖叫声停止]
- Well, that was
anticlimactic.
- 嗯，那是
虎头蛇尾。
- Again.
- 再次。
[grumbling]
- Ho!
[抱怨]
- 嗬！
Ah, ah, ugh, ah!
[punching]
啊啊啊啊啊！
[冲孔]
[vomits]
[呕吐]
[shivering, whimpering]
[颤抖，呜咽]
Ahh!
[cries]
啊！
[哭声]
- Oh, ah--
[punching, straining]
- 哦，啊--
[猛击、用力]
Oh!
哦！
Whoa!
哇！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
[punching]
[冲孔]
Beg to me.
求我吧。
[all exclaiming]
[所有人惊呼]
Whoa!
哇！
Oh!
哦！
[growls]
Oh!
[咆哮]
哦！
Ouch!
Oh!
哎哟!
哦！
Wait a minute!
Gimme that!
等一下！
给我那个！
[bashes]
[重击]
[smashing]
[yells, growls]
[粉碎]
[喊叫，咆哮]
[crashing, squealing]
[撞击声、尖叫声]
[all cheer]
[大家欢呼]
[bubbles popping]
[气泡破裂]
- Here ya go, Mr. Krabs.
You earned it.
- 给你，蟹老板。
你赚到了。
- Well, boy-o,
you believed in me,
- 好吧，男孩，
你相信我，
so today will be
a pay day for you.
所以今天将是
你的发薪日。
- What about me?
- 关于我的什么？
- You,
Ex-Captain Squidward,
- 你，
前章鱼哥船长，
have gone from pay day
to Mayday!
已经从发薪日过去了
到五月天！
Mush!
Every last one of ya!
糊涂！
你们的每一个最后！
All the way
back to Bikini Bottom!
一路走来
回到比基尼泳裤！
[laughs]
[笑]